Oh, it hurts. It hurts. It hurts. Stop with the hurt.
No, but the prophets...
Hearing is good for you. Sometimes you get hurt, you feel better after it.
The prophets insisting...
Let me ask you, if somebody hurts you, right away you can't think because you're hurt.
When the hurt goes away, you start to rethink and you become stronger.
Maybe.
Maybe or yes.
Maybe. If someone hurts me, it depends how hurt I am.
Whatever, if somebody hurts you badly, you become stronger or you become weaker?
Weaker for a time, but then you build resilience.
That's right. That's right.
But hurting is different than killing. You can't come back from murder.
It's not murder. You say murder. You keep saying murder. Killing.
It's not killing, it's not murdering. It's slaughtering, taking care of the animal.
The animal is hurt when he's in the world.
He wants to get a better place, so he gets in a better place.
The animal goes to heaven?
Yes.
Ruach?
It rises to heaven.
Yes.
Okay.
But is that not playing God to take its life and send it to heaven?
That's what God wants.
God wants us to kill the animals and send them to heaven.
Yes. Yes. Come closer to me. Get closer to me.
So we come closer through murder?
Yes.
It's not murder.
You keep saying murder. Murder is when you murder a person, when you slaughter a chicken or you slaughter a bee, whatever you do, you just bring it close.
You get closer to Hashem. Hashem loves it.
But what makes, what makes an animal different from a human that justifies us murdering it, but not a human?
What do you mean? What do you mean?
What is the difference between humans?
Because he made, he gave us our knowledge, our way of thinking in our life.
He didn't give it to them.
Because you have read all those things, and I understand you were reading all those things, and I know all those things.
But it's not how you think, because it's still not straight.
Maybe one day when every sin will be forgiven, forgotten, when the world is going to be pure war.
Then, then we'll go with your argument.
Well, Isaiah went with that idea now.
That's what I'm saying, but it's not yet ready.
Why is it not ready? Can we not choose it?
We are not there yet.
Why is that?
Maybe is it because we're murdering? Thou shalt not murder?
No, no, no, no. Because there's a lot of people who still need to come to us.
Okay.
And they're not there yet. And we want everyone there yet.
Everyone.
Not just Hebrews.
Every, everyone.
When that will happen, you win the argument.
But if God...
If that will happen, you win the argument.
If God created creatures with life, with Ruach and us, the same, we all have nafesh, we all have ruach.
Yes.
So how can I or you take and kill the nafesh or the ruach of this living being?
Let me explain the one thing.
We don't kill.
There is a thing kill.
Kill is a strong word.
We do slaughtering, which is different than killing.
Let me explain.
The animal doesn't feel anything when he gets slaughtered.
Why?
Because the knife that gets slaughtered doesn't have a fix.
Nothing.
It's so...
He doesn't feel a thing when you cut it.
Glass is getting hot.
For best results.
He doesn't feel a thing when you cut it.
You understand?
I know you're recording me.
I know that.
Listen.
Okay.
I don't care.
Because I know where you're going with it.
But the thing is like this.
When you do it in a way our system does it, that means you're doing the way our Sam wants.
How is there a right way to kill?
There's a right way because there's in the Bible.
It says...
But aren't you stealing the life?
We don't steal the life.
The life is not stolen.
The life is...
It's written last year, Rosh Hashanah, or this year, Rosh Hashanah, that this is going to happen.
Everything is written.
Every year, it gets written a new page.
But that's extra writings outside the Torah, outside the 613.
No, that's the right...
We don't write anything.
Hashem does write everything.
Hashem writes with a pen?
Correct.
Where?
You don't have to see it.
You're just witnessing it.
Yeah.
You're witnessing it in the daily life.
Well, the prophets witnessed it too.
And they said, they shall not hurt...
You know, you know, Isaiah, he says, they shall not hurt or slaughter.
Shakat.
It's not the way we do it.
We do it...
No shakat.
No shakat?
Yeah.
They shall not hurt or slaughter on all my holy mountain.
Isaiah.
Right?
But he says, Shakat and Shakitha.
Listen, listen.
No more.
It's not God.
How is that not God?
God desires mercy, not sacrifice.
How do you make pictures?
Huh?
You can see it?
I work for God.
What?
Yeah.
What's God?
Hmm?
Hashem.
The one God.
Yeah.
The God over all life.
How do you give them pictures?
Hmm?
How do I give them?
They record on the camera.
How do you give the pictures of God?
Oh, I make documentaries, movies, for God.
Yeah.
So much movies are gonna make.
How do you smile?
Mm-hmm.
Man.
Who? Hello, who?
Hello, who?
Come on.
Are you ready?
Good job, good job, no man.
You must miss.
You help? You help him?
You love him?
I love him.
Picture?
Who are you shooting for?
I'm trying to make documentaries.
Documentary?
Like movies?
Yeah, for God, yeah.
Your own movie?
Make your own movie.
What about Kaporos?
Oh, yeah.
Make a documentary on Kaporos.
Oh, wow, man.
You don't write?
Make a documentary for yourself?
For someone or for yourself?
For myself, on Kaporos, yeah.
I study the Hebrew Bible.
You're Jewish.
I'm not Jewish by blood, no.
No, your mother is not Jewish?
No.
But I read the Tanakh.
Yeah.
Where is this ritual in the Tanakh, though?
It's a whole thing.
It's not only in the Judaism.
It's also in the Catholicism that you take off the sin from yourself.
You put it on the chicken and you eat the chicken for the purpose of good reason.
Whatever.
It's just the whole thing in it.
So the sin transfers to the chicken?
You transfer it, but you don't do it, but you don't want to just transfer it.
You want to eat the soul from the chicken.
You eat the soul?
You eat the chicken, not the soul.
You eat the chicken.
Okay.
You transfer the sin and you eat the chicken.
Oh, so you eat your own chicken that you kill?
Yeah.
Not necessarily the own.
It's all the chicken that has a cup of rice.
Okay.
But these chickens, because this is a slaughterhouse?
Yes.
Right here?
So do these chickens just go to slaughter for everyone in the ritual, or is it sold?
It's not sold.
It's donated?
They both donated.
Okay.
Where is it donated?
The people who need.
Okay.
But the people in need, are they then eating the sin?
It's not they eating the sin.
It's not.
Yeah.
The sin gets when you slaughter the chicken, then the sin gets out, because the blood gets
out.
So the sin is in the blood?
Yes.
It is in the blood.
Okay.
So the sin is in the blood, or it cleanses the blood?
Or the blood cleanses the sin?
The blood cleanses the sin.
Okay.
You know Leviticus 5:11?
Right?
Because you're...
Yeah, yeah.
I'm listening.
Because you're giving the...
You're giving it to the poor, right?
In Leviticus 5:11, you can do a sin cleansing with only grain, no blood.
There is...
Also, when you give a donation, it's the same thing.
Okay.
When you give money, let's say for the poor, it's the same thing.
So then why is the chicken necessary?
So it has a meaning.
What's the meaning?
I'm trying to learn.
I'm listening.
You want to go into it?
Yeah.
Okay.
The meaning is that every, every, every, every, every, every life thing has a soul.
Ruach.
Yeah.
So it has a purpose that needs to be done in life.
But its purpose is life, right?
Not death?
No, no, no, no, no.
It's death definitely because, because it's made for human to eat.
Okay.
It's a, a chicken, the same thing with beef.
It's the same thing is made and you should take out the blood from it.
We don't eat the blood.
The blood we're not allowed to eat.
Yeah.
The life is in the blood.
Ruach is in the blood.
Yes.
So we don't eat the blood.
So, but you can drain.
We drain the blood.
How does all the blood get out of the meat?
So, listen to what we do.
After everything we sold the chicken.
We sold the meat.
And it sits an hour in the soul.
Uh-huh.
The soul sunctions out the blood.
All of it?
All of it.
Even the capillaries?
So once it's out, you're allowed to eat it. If it's in there, you're not allowed to eat it.
But God created the world in Genesis 1, right? Genesis 1?
What do you mean by that?
The creation narrative is in Genesis chapter 1.
God gives dominion, right?
So God gives dominion, Genesis 1:26-28.
Then Genesis 1:29, it's a plant-based paradise, no slaughter, no animals eaten.
No, no, it's not true. Because we can see we have done the sacrifice.
You ever heard of sacrifice?
Yes. This is a sacrifice.
This is a sacrifice. There is a sacrifice in the history that we did in the Basimikdos.
Have you ever heard that we sacrificed? We bring in the cows, we bring in the cows,
and we did this in the beginning because God wants us to eat the thing.
Well, in Genesis 1, before sin, you talk about the verse of capitalism.
It's not Judaism. It's different.
Judaism doesn't... Jews don't read Genesis?
No. Not reality.
It's in the Pentateuch.
I know, but it's not our thing.
Genesis isn't your thing.
Genesis is not our thing. We have the Bible.
That's the most important thing.
The Tanakh?
No, the Tanakh. The original Bible.
The Hebrew Bible.
Genesis is in the Hebrew Bible.
No, but that's somebody else take her out.
Took her out.
They did?
Yes.
Who?
The Tanakh is not from Hashem.
It's people who created it.
Oh, okay.
They're different.
Okay.
So what...
Hashem gave out the Torah.
The Torah.
The Torah, the 613 laws?
613 laws.
That's correct.
So only the laws are Hashem, not the Pentateuch.
Not the Pentateuch.
That's correct.
Interesting.
Well, Yeremiyahu, Jeremiah, the prophet, he speaks for Hashem.
I know.
I know, but it's still not Hashem.
It's still not Hashem.
Well, Jeremiah, Yeremiyahu, says in chapter 7, verse 22, that God did not command sacrifice.
What about Hosea?
The same thing.
6:6.
The only thing is Moses.
But Moses brought them out of Egypt.
Right?
He brought them out of Egypt.
But Moses did everything.
Straight the line.
He didn't go there.
He didn't go...
He didn't move up there.
Straight it.
Well, Jeremiah said on the day when I called you out of Egypt, I did not command your fathers,
as in Moses, concerning burnt offerings or sacrifices.
I only commanded them obey my voice and I will be your God and you will be my people.
And Hosea says that God desires mercy, not sacrifice.
Hesed.
Hesed?
Yeah.
Hesed, correct.
Not sacrifice.
Hesed is the same thing when you donate.
When you donate a chicken, let's say somebody needs to eat.
I understand you're a vegan.
Huh?
Well, no, I'm...
You are a vegan.
Hey, don't you...
You're a vegan.
I'm a child of God and these are creatures of God.
No, no, no, no.
You're mixing up.
The thing is like this.
You think your brain is the smartest.
No.
I don't think that.
No, I think Hashem's way is the smartest.
The way of life.
Hashem's way is the smartest.
And Hashem says, eat the animals.
Where?
In the Torah.
There's just a lot of places.
So you follow only the 613 laws.
100%.
But you don't read Genesis, you don't read the prophets.
The other thing is not necessary.
It's not necessary.
But to the prophets it was, no?
Listen, they have their things.
They have their ways.
They have their agendas.
They have their things.
It's not the same.
It's still not the same.
I'm pretty certain that Jews read the Pentateuch.
Some do, some...
I'm not saying nobody's really...
Whatever.
All those things.
People like to have knowledge and have understanding.
They like to read any book and whatever it says.
But it doesn't mean that you should go away from the original.
Yeah.
What about Isaiah?
Isaiah?
You have to stay to the original.
What about...
Isaiah?
Isaiah.
Isaiah, yeah.
I hear you.
Stay to the original.
Yeah, but Isaiah 1:11 says that God...
Listen, listen.
We are not gonna win this argument.
You know too much. You're way too far. I see you all the way. I see you through 100. You're a good guy. I'm not going to argue. You're a good guy.
Yeah. Well, what I see is I think the 613 laws, the 10 words are from God.
Correct.
Yes.
But the rest of the ritual and tradition, that's addition onto the 10 words.
But that's taken out from the 10 words. It's taken out from the 10 words.
How?
Everything.
Glass is getting hot. For best results, let them cool.
I'm gone. Let's say yes. It says,
From that word, we take out what does it mean. The meaning of it. Everything has meaning.
All the words have been written to 613. The whole 10 commitments have been written to the whole 613.
Yes. Right. But if you sum them up, like, I know you're not as big of a fan of Yeshu, Hanotzeri, Jesus the Nazarene, but he said the greatest command.
Listen, he could have been the Jesus. I'm not saying not.
Mashiach.
He could have been the Mashiach, but he wasn't. He failed. He failed.
But what does it mean he failed? Because he brought down the temple and the sacrifice.
What it means he failed, he went against God.
How?
By thinking that he is God.
Where does it say that he is God?
He was thinking that.
Huh?
He had that in his mind.
He had that. You shouldn't have that in your mind.
Well, if you read the true writings.
But that's where he went. And he went wrong with it.
He went wrong with it.
I see him as Messiah.
Mashiach.
Not God.
God the Father.
Abba.
He said Abba.
I hear you.
So many others say that.
Yeah.
Hashem.
Abba.
Yeah.
He cited the Shema.
I hear you.
He said, hear Israel.
The Lord our God is one.
You know what?
I know his Neshoma.
Huh?
What?
I said, I know his Neshoma.
Neshoma?
Neshoma.
What is that?
You know what?
Every person has a Neshoma.
No.
Neshoma is the soul.
Oh, yeah.
Nefesh.
Yeah.
You know.
How do you know it?
Secret.
Secret?
What's the secret?
Gotta wait it out.
Glass is getting hot.
For best results, let them cool.
Is it some kind of like Kabbalah or something?
Yes.
Yes?
So you know the soul of Jesus through Kabbalah.
What did you learn?
Kabbalah.
Like what?
Everything goes through.
Everything goes through the woman.
Okay.
What does that have to do with Yeshu?
Everything has to do with the person.
Thanks, thanks, thanks, thanks, thanks.
I would like to get your number.
Um, what does everything going through the woman have to do with Yeshu?
Because the woman healed the world.
The woman killed the world?
Healed.
Healed the world.
Yes.
Okay.
How does the woman heal the world?
And what does that have to do with Yeshu?
Because whoever was not married has the issue of seeing the whole picture.
Well, what if Jesus was married to Migdal, Maria?
That's the issue.
Because it was a whole issue.
What was the issue?
You know that.
You know that that is a mix.
I don't know.
What do you mean you don't know?
So you're saying if you're not married, that's a problem.
Right.
But what if Yeshu was married to Migdal, Maria?
Well, she wasn't able to heal him.
To heal him?
Yes.
Oh, you mean after the crucifixion?
Not after the glory either.
Heal him of?
It's like this.
A man is a devil, and a woman is a traitor.
Yeah.
You know that.
Yeah?
A woman takes it in and heals it out.
A man gives...
By them, it didn't work that way.
But what if it did?
If it did, then we'd have a different world.
If it didn't work that way.
Well, who's to say it's not a different world,
but everyone who's followed hasn't chosen it
because we're still murdering God's creatures?
No, that's just the thing that you decided.
Because Jesus came...
Yes, you, yes, you.
Yes, you.
He's not alive, and that's it.
That's the end of the story.
Well, he's alive even through us, through me.
No.
He's not alive.
It's only imagination.
Okay.
It's not a real thing.
Is it imagination that our sins go into the chicken?
That's what you have from Kabbalah.
Kabbalah says something to talk about.
No, it's not just a thing.
It's okay.
It has a lot of food.
It says...
Kabbalah says that the sins go into the chicken?
Oh, it comes from Kabbalah.
I see.
What proof is there that the sins go into the chicken?
Kabbalah.
Well, you could say the same thing,
that there's proof that yes, you ended sacrifice.
And that...
It's imagination.
But how is that imagination,
but sins going into the chicken isn't?
Because...
You're just appealing to one holy book.
No.
Because there's only one...
Or oral tradition.
There's only one that's never been changed.
Kabbalah.
Not only Kabbalah.
I said the Bible was changing it.
Okay.
It's only that then you make it...
Old Testament, New Testament, they're changing...
That's crap.
Yeah.
That's not before...
Have you heard of the Moses scroll?
Found...
It's a Deuteronomic...
Like Deuteronomy scroll.
First person handed Moses, found in the 1800s in Moab.
And it has no animal sacrifice.
What if Moses never commanded animal sacrifice?
You could see the sacrifice on Abraham.
Abraham did the sacrifice on the mountain for Isaac.
He's supposed to do it on Isaac.
And then he did it.
And God says, no, don't do it on Isaac.
Do it on animal.
But if you read the text, Hashem never asked him to sacrifice the ram.
Yes.
Abraham finds the ram.
And then Abraham says, God has provided.
So it's Abraham's idea, not God's.
But Abraham was a man of God.
Well, Abraham did a lot of things, didn't he?
Abraham was a man of God.
Okay.
Nobody could touch Hashem.
Abraham was the man of God.
The first person who ever found God.
Whoever found...
What about Melchizedek?
Not the same.
Yeah.
But he's a priest before Abraham.
No, but that's only...
It's also imagination.
It's imagination.
Melchizedek is Midrash.
Okay.
It's imagination.
Oh, imagination.
Yes.
Oh.
Melchizedek is imagination.
It's imagination.
Abraham's not imagination.
No, absolutely not.
Okay.
Abraham, Isaac, Jacob, Joseph was not imagination.
What about in Leviticus?
It also says, like Yeshu, to love your neighbor as yourself.
That is good.
That's a good line.
Yeah.
That's a great line.
We love...
Listen...
Animals are our neighbors.
I love you.
Everybody, we love you.
We're not here today.
But chickens are our neighbors.
They have a soul in Nafesh.
They're our neighbor.
It's not the same.
Neighbor is a...
If they would do the same, they would defend themselves.
Hmm?
They can't defend themselves.
Well, they try.
They scream for their lives.
No, they don't scream.
They're screaming for their lives here.
They're screaming.
Take me in.
Take me in?
Yes.
That doesn't sound like take me in.
That sounds like they're hurting.
Listen, I could listen to that.
They have gashes and they're missing their toes.
Hmm.
The word neighbor, it's in Hebrew.
It just slipped my mind.
Neighbor.
No.
Neighbor means sukh in Hebrew.
In Hebrew.
No.
Raya.
Raya also.
Raya, yeah.
Raya is one near to us.
Close to us.
So bring it in.
Huh?
But how do you bring something in by killing it?
Because...
You bring it in by loving and nurturing and serving.
By eating it.
So the only way to be close to a neighbor is eating them?
Eating them.
Well, then why aren't you eating them?
Why?
Because they are the same like us.
You don't touch them.
Yeah.
They are not the same.
You know about the history of the Nephilim?
No.
Huh?
In Genesis, no?
The Nephilim?
No, I haven't.
The sons of gods, angels that fall, mate with human women and create giants?
I don't know.
It's where the story of the Amalekites comes from?
- Nephilim.
- Huh?
- Never heard of it.
- You never heard of Nephilim?
Huh? Giants.
In Jerusalem?
Yeah, the giants, Nephilim.
Okay, okay, yes, I agree.
Yeah, and Goliath.
Okay, yes.
Yeah, these Nephilim.
Yes.
They're created from fallen angels.
That's why the spies said that it's not the place to go.
Yeah.
That's why.
But you know, in Genesis 6, it says that the Nephilim taught violence and bloodshed to the world
and how to sacrifice animals.
It's in Enoch as well.
You know Enoch.
The book of Enoch.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Enoch 7, 14.
Anyway, it's a pleasure.
I have to go to work also.
Okay.
Are you slaughtering in here?
Not yet, no.
No?
Can I see the slaughter?
No.
It's better for you not to see.
Why?
Because you're too against it.
No.
You're too against it.
I'll watch it.
I know you watch it.
But your mindset is too against it.
No, I've seen kosher slaughter.
Kashrut.
Yeah.
Yeah, but I don't want to take pictures.
The guys don't like pictures.
It's nice.
They don't want it.
Okay.
Why not?
They are very holy.
And pictures is not the holiest thing for them.
Are you sure?
I really want to see it.
I know, but I'm telling you.
I'm telling you.
You're at Joseph, yeah?
Yes.
Joseph, we're friends.
I know.
I'm telling you, but they won't.
Can you ask them if I can just see them?
No, they won't allow it.
I know.
I have a headspace.
Some people ask me before that.
Yeah.
Well, on Saturday for Yom Kippur, they're going to slaughter in the streets, yeah?
Yes.
Yeah?
So then I can see it there.
Yeah.
Where's the place for that?
We've got to check it out.
I don't know.
Because there's this location, but how many other locations?
This is one location.
It has nothing to do with others.
Okay.
This is a location all year around.
We're not here all year now.
We do it all year.
Okay.
I thought it was for Yom Kippur, though.
No, we do it all year.
You do the ritual?
Not the Kippur, but we do the slogans.
We do it all year.
We're a life poetry.
Okay.
I see.
Oh, so you work for the shop?
Yeah, this is my shop.
Okay.
I understand.
Well.
But I don't speak as because it's my shop.
I want to defend my shop.
Yeah.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm not speaking like that.
But what if, I have this, what if, last thing.
What if the prophets were right?
What if the prophets were right and God never wanted sacrifice?
God wanted us to serve.
You know, we are in a time, right now, the greatest time we live in.
It's, it's, it's near, we are ending the near, near...
An age.
An age, yeah.
Yeah.
So, we are taking a good...
The age where sacrifice is over.
Okay.
Well, let's live it now.
No, no.
We still have to wait it out.
Why?
I told you.
What if we delay the age by killing?
No, no.
We don't delay the age.
By uniting the world, once the world is united...
But how do we unite if we're killing?
No, because that's not...
Because we are still, we are still, people still need to get out a lot of hate who they have
inside.
We have to...
But isn't it hateful to kill an animal?
No, it's not hateful to kill an animal.
Because an animal is not hateful because I told you again, it's in the Torah, Abraham did
it, so we know that it's not...
But when, but before even Abraham did it, Noah did it.
True.
After the flood.
And God was angry.
Because, because, because that's a different story.
Because Noah was a good man, but he wasn't Abraham.
Hmm.
Abraham was the man of God.
So if you're a man of God, then you sacrifice?
I thought if you're a man of God, you don't need to sacrifice because mercy is better than
sacrifice.
Man of God, you do what God wants, and then anything you do, God likes.
Okay.
Well, if God wants murdered animals, then what does Hashatan want?
Satan.
Satan wants only to think, look for negativity.
But what's more negative than taking away the life of a creature?
It's not negativity, it's positivity, because it gives you life, and it's what you live in.
And you eat, you eat, and Abraham gave you, gave you, gave you something to eat.
He gave you something to do, whatever, what's necessarily in the world.
So, so you don't take Genesis 1 seriously then?
No, correct.
Even though it's a priestly source.
No, no, but it's not what God wants.
Genesis 1, well, Genesis 1 isn't about what God wants, but it's about what God created.
God created that for the animals that we should eat them.
That's why he created us.
We should eat them.
But where are you getting that from?
From the Torah.
In the 613 laws, it doesn't say God created animals to eat them.
No, but in the Torah, you see that that's what we did all the time.